Benjamin Maccini

I'm a Texan and a programmer with experience in startups, early-stage product development, algorithms and machine learning. I have spent time in the restaurant industry, local food systems and in retail. Food and food-related technologies are my passion.

□ benjaminmaccini@gmail.com

L +15127053797 **Q** CST

github.com/benjaminmaccini

WORK EXPERIENCE

unPLUG Dining

Nov 2021 - Dec 2023 Founding Engineer

- unPLUG is a Chicago-based tech company developing an omnichannel, data-driven, digital software platform that automates, personalizes, and optimizes the restaurant dining experience.
- Helped grow engineering team to 12+ people
- Worked on anything and everything from standing up our cloud to writing recommender algorithms with a focus on developer productivity and shipping well-tested platform APIs.

Live Oak Data LLC

Owner May 2021 - Nov 2021

 Live Oak Data is a boutique data labeling service. We curate high accuracy datasets for human-in-the-loop machine learning.

Pensa Systems

Jun 2019 - Jun 2020 Software Engineer

- Pensa Systems is a retail technology company, providing meaningful insights into current shelf conditions using computer vision and machine learning.
- Created diagnostic tooling for runtime object localization services
- Evaluation and QA of deep learning models for information retrieval and object categorization.
- Implemented a custom 3D scene reconstruction algorithm
- Productionized research-oriented Python code, effectively eliminating runtime failure

Intern/Contractor Feb 2018 - Jun 2019

- Led the coordination of independent contractors for the purpose of data collection and data labelling
- Engaged in field operations for experimental hardware trials

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Austin

B.S. in Mathematics, Minor in Business

May 2019

SKILLS

- Services [AWS, CircleCI, Github, Terraform Cloud, PostgreSQL]
- Languages [Modern Python, Go, HCL, SQL]
- Methodologies [REST, Microservices, AGILE, TDD, OKRs, OOP, FP]
- Domain Knowledge [Ordering systems, Payments, Loyalty programs, Hierarchical data modeling, Data labeling services, Retail inventory systems]
- Non-"Technical" [Cooking, Non-profit work at farmers markets, High-rise window washing, Route-cleaning at climbing gym, working knowledge in Latin American Spanish]